## **BRIAN TALBOT**

617-733-4900 32 Sherman St. Cambridge, MA 02138 brian.r.talbot@gmail.com talbs.me/work

I've helped a wide range of businesses and organizations – from big brands to non-profits to startups – create engaging, user-friendly experiences that balance business goals, user needs and goals, and technical capabilities.

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

## Design Lead, edX

2012 - 2015 Cambridge, MA

As part of MIT's non-profit organization, I lead the interaction and visual design of edX's educational products to help millions of people both learn and teach new concepts and subjects. Recently, I've directed the strategy and implementation of edX's Pattern Library, planning an inventory of patterns, providing interaction and visual design for each, and writing modern, accessible, deployable, and themeable Front End code. Mentoring UX team members, I've set standards around UX deliverables as well as organized design activities such as studios, reviews, and team skill building exercises.

## User Experience Design Lead, ThinkGeek

2011 - 2012 Fairfax, VA

As the UX lead on ThinkGeek's Customer Experience Team, my role involved overseeing the Information Architecture and User Interface Design of the company's e-commerce site. Along with leading the design of strategic projects, monitoring performance, and supporting ThinkGeek's high level of customer satisfaction online, I built a foundation to the team's design process and strategic collaboration with other departments.

## Senior User Experience Designer, Viget

2009 – 2011 Falls Church, VA

At Viget, my primary responsibilities included leading the UX phase of projects where I helped clients research, plan online strategies and information architectures, and design interactions and interfaces. I worked with a variety of clients including PUMA, National Geographic, The Sundance Institute, Compassion International, and Choice Hotels.

## Web Designer/Developer, National Geographic

2007 - 2009 Washington, DC

At National Geographic, I directed the strategy, implementation, and team responsible for front-end development of National Geographic's Digital Media properties including national geographic.com. Alongside those duties, I led the strategy, information architecture, and interaction/visual design phases for strategic projects and initiatives.

## Web Designer/Developer, Simmons College

2003 - 2007 Boston, MA

While at Simmons, I grew into a senior role that led direction, strategy, information architecture and design on key projects. I co-created an award-winning admissions-focused web presence, held design and development faculty and staff training, and led a cross-functional web accessibility working group.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Library & Information Science, Simmons College

2004 - 2006 Bd

Bachelor of Arts Psychology and Studio Art, College of the Holy Cross

1998 – 2002 Worcester, MA

#### **NOTEWORTHY SKILLS**

Design Research
Information Achitecture
Content Strategy
Interaction & UI Design
Visual Design
HTML, Sass/Less/CSS, JavaScript

Project Management

Design Direction & Standards

Design Mentorship & Education

#### ELSEWHERE

# National Geographic Photo Camp

I helped lead several domestic and international workshops to mentor and inspire at-risk and refugee youth to explore their communities creatively through a camera's lens.

### Adjunct Faculty, Boston University CDA

As part of Boston University's Center for Digital Arts, I taught several technical, creative, and strategic-focused courses within their web design program.